FAITH TEBATSO MOICHELA

13 Education St, 308 on Kern, Belhar, Cape Town,7493

CONTACT DETAILS

+27 66 511 0736

4218138@myuwc.ac.za
OR tebatso247@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/faith-tebatso-moichela-7b4a36125

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

During my 8-year stint in the academic sphere, teaching, mentoring, supervising, assessing, collaborating, designing, and overseeing projects, access, processes, and activities has enhanced my ability to build and nurture relationships. Furthermore, as a professional scientific liaison for undergraduate teams, I have successfully trained medical, nursing, optometry, biokinetics, physiotherapy, and dietetics students in anatomy and physiology concepts., I learned to identify unique methods, tools, and pedagogical approaches and tailor solutions to meet the needs of both lecturers and students. My consultative adeptness which is enriched by a circle of peers and experts in the academic sphere of teaching and research has deepened my capacity to effectively communicate, respond, educate, debate, brainstorm, and share information. I am looking for roles in which I will continue to provide high throughput and meaningful contributions through leadership, scholarship, and collaboration using updated practical manuals and virtual tools.

SKILLS

Teaching and learning	Research and Professional Skills	
Emotional intelligence and accountability	Research methodologies, project design, and	
	conceptualization	
Organizational and Communication skills	Data collection, organization, analysis, and presentation	
Teamwork and Independence	Statistical modeling and forecasting	
Tact and patience	Fundamentals of plant extraction	
Coordination and facilitation	Statistical analysis and modeling, study design, and	
	protocol development, systematic reviewing of scientific	
	literature and academic writing	
Public speaking	Mammalian tissue culture, cell biology, qPCR, SDS page,	
Communication and Collaboration	spectrophotometry, flow cytometry, basic microscopy,	
	semen analysis, laboratory inventory and management	

EXPERIENCE

University of the Western Cape

Teaching assistant and tutor

Feb 2022-Present

- Assist with the development and implementation of educational technology and online learning.
- Assist with assessment/to assess students' work under supervision
- Monitor and evaluate students' responses to learning activities through observation
- Provision of feedback to students in relation to progress and achievement.
- Provision of additional/individual/out-of-class-time support to students.
- Assistance with the management of tutors as well as coordinating the tutorial sessions
- Determination of need, preparation and supply of additional resources or equipment for students
- Keeping, reviewing, and updating students' records in agreement with the lecturer

University of the Free State

Professional officer for Physiology

Oct 2019–Jan 2022

- Teaching and demonstration of laboratory safety practices and basic microscopy, pipetting physiology Honours Skills program
- Marking and verifying assignments, tutorials, practical marks, etc.
- Health safety representative for the Physiology laboratory
- Updating electronic software utilized in practicals and tutoring sessions.
- Ensure functionality and arrange for repairs and upgrades of computational systems and machinery in the lab.
- Evaluating/assessing objective structured clinical examinations (OSCEs) and objective structured practical examinations (OSPEs) in the clinical skills unit
- Physiology laboratory inventory keeping and ordering of equipment, chemicals, and consumables
- Practical demonstration using ADinstruments LabTutor and Lt (virtual) tools.
- Screening prospective Honours Physiology applications

University of Limpopo Laboratory Assistant

Feb 2017- Sep 2019

- Laboratory equipment and automated machine operation
- Laboratory inventory keeping, quoting, specimen, and chemical handling.
- Demonstration of Anthropometric measurement, ECG, BP, blood glucose measurements, peripheral and autonomous perception physiology tests (CNS/PNS), and muscle physiology practical.
- Assisting students with modular content
- Administrative work e.g., marking, invigilation, memoranda compilation, data capturing, and pre-lab presentations.
- Procedure demonstration and safety laboratory and housekeeping monitoring

EDUCATION

University of the Western Cape

2022 - Present

Ph.D. Medical Biosciences

Male reproduction and the endocannabinoid system

University of Limpopo

2018 - 2020

MSc Medical Sciences *

In vitro effects of Moringa oleifera on human sperm functions

University of Limpopo

2017-2017

BSc Hons Human Physiology

Majors: Chronic diseases and toxicity, Occupation Health and hygiene, Reproduction

University of Limpopp

2014 - 2016

BSc Life Sciences

Majors: <u>Human Physiology and Biochemistry</u>

Kgoke High School

REFERENCE

Dr. Liana Maree	Mr. Dean Solomons	Dr. Jino Mundackal	Dr. Sanet van Zyl
Senior Lecturer	Senior Scientific Officer	Senior Lecturer	HOD
Department of Medical	Department of Medical	Department of	Department of Basic
Biosciences	Biosciences	Physiology and	Medical Sciences
		Environmental Health	
University of the Western			
Cape			
	University of the Western		
	Cape	University of Limpopo	
			University of the Free
021 959 2917/ 083 556			State
1496	021 959 3062/061 140		
	5882	015 268 3993/082 558	
		9914	082 9000 5702/051 401
			7880
<u>lmaree@uwc.ac.za</u>	desolomons@uwc.ac.za	jino.mundackal@ul.ac.za	gnfssvz@ufs.ac.za

TRANSCRIPTS AND CERTIFICATES

Available upon request